So, we can do another example of defining a recursive
我们开始练习另一个关于定义递归过程的例子
procedure. And the goal this time is to take in
这次我们的目标是输入
a string, and determine whether or not it's a palindrome.
一个字符串 然后决定它是否属于回文
What a palindrome is, is a string that reads the same
回文的概念是 阅读该字符串 它始终是同样的意思
way, forwards and backwards. So, an example of a palindrome
不管是正向还是逆向 现在我给出一个回文的例子
would be level. If we read level forwards, we get
就是 level 这个词 如果我们正向读 level 这个词 我们会得到
level If we read it backwards, we get exactly the
level 这个词 如果我们反向读这个词 恰好得到的也是 level 这个词
same thing. Another example of a palindrome would be the word,
也就是同一个词 另一个属于回文的例子是这个词
the single letter a. If we read a forwards, we
we 单字母 a 如果我们正向去读这个词
get a. If we read a backwards, we also get
我们会得到 a  如果我们反向读呢 还是得到 a 这个词
a. In fact, any single letter must be a palindrome.
实际上 任何一个单字母肯定属于回文
The empty string is also a palindrome. If we read
空字符也属于回文 如果我们
the empty string forward, we have the empty string, if
正向去读空字符串 我们得到的是空字符串 如果
we read the string backward, we also have empty string.
我们反向读空字符串 我们也是得到一个空字符串
So, our goal is to define a procedure that will
所以我们的目标是定义一个过程 输入
take any string as input and output true if that string
任何字符串 然后返回逻辑真的结果 如果
is a palindrome. I am going to view, give you a few hints how
输入的字符串是回文 我将会给你一些提示
to do this, but start thinking on your own, if you can think
关于完成这个过程的提示 但是你要先自己思考 如果你能想出
of a way to define a procedure that tests whether or not a
一种方式来定义测试输入字符串是否属于回文的过程
string is a palindrome. So, this is a pretty tough question. See how far
这是一个相当难的问题 看一下你能
you can get on your own, but I'm going to provide some hints before
通过自己的思考能想到哪一步 但是在提问前我将提供一些指示
we make the quiz. So, the first hint is, we want to think
第一个指示是 我们要思考
of what it means to be a palindrome. To try to formalize that
回文的概念是什么 我们要将这个概念形式化
definition, if we knew easy ways to produce the reverse of the string, and
以及我们是否知道如何简单地生成输入字符串的反向形式
check if it's equal. Well that would be an easy way
随后再测试它与输入字符串是否相等 好 有这么一个简单的方法
to solve this, and in fact there are ways to do that
可以解决这个问题 实际上有很多方法可以完成这个任务
in Python. But we haven't seen them yet. And I want to
在 Python 这门语言里 但是我们还没有接触过这些方法 而我想要
have you think about ways to do this palindrome that don't depend
让你想出判断回文的其他方式 而且不用依赖这些方法
on that. So, that means we need to think about a
所以 我们需要思考出
way of defining a palindrome in terms of simpler things. So, the
一种按照简单的方法去判断回文字符串的定义
first thing to notice is, there's one simple case where we know
所以第一个要注意的点是 我们现在就知道有一个简单的情况
right away whether a string's a palindrome. So, we should think that
用来判断字符串是否为回文 所以我们应该想出
that might be our base case. When we do
这就是我们递归定义中的基本情况 当我们执行
procedures on numbers our base case is often something
关于数字处理的过程时 我们的基本情况经常是某些
that deals with a number like zero or one,
处理像 0 或者 1 这样的数字
a small number. When we do recursive procedures on strings,
一个规模小的数字 当我们执行处理字符串的递归过程时
it's more likely that our base case is going to
那很可能我们的基本情况会是
be the simpler string, which is the empty string. So,
一个更简单的字符串 也就是空字符串 所以
we know that if the input is an empty
我们知道如果输入的字符串为空字符串时
string, the result of this palindrome is true. The empty
这个回文过程的返回值应该为逻辑真 也就是说空字符串
string is a palindrome. What if the input's not an empty
属于回文 如果输入字符串不是空字符串
string. Well then, one way to solve that would be to
好了 解决这种输入的一种方法是
look at the first letter of the string, and look at
观察字符串的第一个字符 然后观察
the last letter of the string. If those two are equal.
字符串的最后一个字符 如果这两个字符相等
Well, then it might be a palindrome. It's a palindrome if
好 那它就可能是一个回文 要肯定这个字符串是回文的话
all the ones left over in the middle are also a
这个单词余下的中间部分也应该是回文
palindrome. So, this is how we could break the question of
所以这就是我们解决
testing whether a string's a palindrome into smaller steps, that our
测试一个字符串是否为回文的几个小步骤 我们的
recursive case is going to test the first and the last
递归情况将会是测试第一个和最后一个
character of the string, see if those are equal, so if
字符串中的字符 判断它们是否相等 如果
our recursive case. We're going to test the first and the last
我们执行到递归情况 我们会测试第一个和最后一个
characters of the string. If those don't match, we know it's
字符串中的字母 如果它们的值不匹配 我们就知道这个字符串
not a palindrome. That means we know the result is
不是回文 也就是我们的结果应该为
false. If they do match, we're not done. We need to
逻辑假 如果它们的值匹配的话 我们还没完成任务 我们需要
check the rest of the string. And that means, we need
测试字符串的剩余部分 也就是说 我们需要
to check the middle of the string, if that's a palindrome.
测试字符串的中间部分 测试它是否属于回文
And because we're able to define this recursively, remember that
因为我们可以递归地定义这个过程 我们要记住
we're defining the procedure is_palindrome, but we can do this test
我们在定义 is_palindrom 这个过程 但是我们可以这样执行字符串中间部分的测试
assuming that we've already defined it. In order to check whether
假设我们已经定义了 is_palindrome 这个过程 为了测试
the middle of the string is a palindrome we can use
字符串的中间部分是否为回文 我们可以调用
the procedure that we're defining. This is like we were
我们正在定义的这个过程 这就好像我们
able to use factorial to define factorial in terms of a
可以使用 factorial 过程来定义针对更小数字的 factorial 过程
smaller number. In this case, we're defining a palindrome in terms
在这个例子中 我们正在定义一个
of the smaller string. So, I hope this is enough for
处理更小规模字符串的判断回文过程 希望我给出的提示足够你
you to get started, so see if you
开始 is_palindrome 过程的定义任务 接下来看看你是否
can define the code for is_palindrome, keeping in mind
定义 is_palindrom 过程的代码 记住
that we can break it down into these two cases where if it's empty, we know it's
我们可以拆分过程为两种情况 如果输入的是空字符串 我们知道
a palindrome right away, if it's not empty,
它肯定是一个回文 如果字符串不为空
well, we need to look at that first and
好 我们需要观察第一个字符和
last characters. If they do match, we also
最后一个字符 如果它们的值匹配的话 我们还要
need to look at the middle of the string.
继续观察字符串的中间部分